Jonathan Robert Cable

Round Rock, Texas me@joncable.com (512) 426-4132

Objective

Seasoned web professional who thrives in creative environments and provides rich experiences in web, print and information technologies. With a background in Linux systems, Software architecture and networking provide a rounded background that is invaluable in today's fast paced environments.

Skill Sets

Programming Languages / Database Technologies

- HTML5/CSS3/jQuery/PHP
- Perl/Python/Bash
- Operating Systems / Web Server Environments
 - Amazon Cloud Service Deployment
 - Unix (CentOS, RedHat, Fedora)
 - Windows NT+, OSX10+
- Content Management / Web Applications / Libraries
 - Wordpress / Joomla / Drupal
 - Laravel / Zend / Codeignitor
 - BootStrap / jQueryUI
- **Productivity Software Applications**
 - Adobe Creative Suite
 - Jetbrains PhpStorm / PyCharm

- MySQL/PostgreSQL/SQLite3
- MSSQL/Access
- Secure SSL/LAMP Environments
- Video Streaming Environments
- Plesk and CPanel Management (API)
- FFMPEG / h264/MPEG Libraries
- Darwin / Quicktime / VLC (headless)
- Open/Libre Office (headless)
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Atlassian Software Suite

Education

May 2008 BS - Technical Management Devry University

Graduate with Honors, Summa Cum Laude: Global Business Minor

May 2003 AAS - Computer Information Systems University of Houston

Graduate with Honors, Summa Cum Laude: Microsoft Networking Specialization

May 2002 CCNA Certificate - Network Technology North Harris College

Certificate earned 4.0 average; *Specialization* in basic router technology.

Work Experience

Oct 2014 – Current Technical Consultant
Web Application Architect Austin, Texas

As a full stack open source web developer since '01 I have had the unique opportunity to see the good, bad and ugly of web development. As a consultant my goal is to diversify my business opportunities and seek start-up or contract opportunities that may potentially lead to more vested business discussions.

Highlights of Responsibilities

- Software Architecture Planning and Release Scheduling.
- Cloud Architecture (HIPAA/PCI) Vormetric Security.
- Full Stack Open Source Application Development.

Oct 2013 – Oct 2014 Director Design & Development

A full-service agency specializing in Search Engine Optimization, Pay Per Click, Content Creation and Social Marketing. Working with multiple teams of developers, designers and marketing professionals I managed the scope and direction of all development, design and systems.

Highlights of Responsibilities

- Manage on-site/off-shore development, design and technical staff.
- Facilitated client and internal projects and production schedules.
- Maintain and improve internal production tools and applications.

May 2009 – Oct 2013 Web Director & Technical Manager Photon Factory, LLC Austin, Texas

Web director of Unity (web), LIVS (video) and operations manager of IC3D (server/client) systems. Unity, LIVS and IC3D software suites are focused on servicing the offshore engineering industries with on location document controls, live/recorded video and 3D modeling/manipulation tools.

Highlights of Responsibilities

- Lead direction of all web and open source technologies
- Technical management of techs, software and remote operations
- Architecture of web applications into Amazon Web Services (EC2,S3,EBS).

June 2004 – May 2009 Information Technology / Web Director Publications & Communications Inc Austin, Texas

Key manager responsible for the daily business and technical operations of a fast paced national magazine publisher. Working closely with executive publishers, sales/marketing managers and art directors to maintain consistent results across print and web environments.

Highlights of Responsibilities

- Subscription Database management, distribution and fulfillment services.
- Manage corporate web portfolio: design, development, systems
- Direction of email, fax & online marketing campaigns

Apr 2003 – Dec 2003 Account Executive Sai People Solutions Kingwood, Texas

Manage web sales and development contracts: sales, marketing and web development specialist for web division of Sai People Solutions.

Highlights of Responsibilities

- Discovered new clients through innovative discovery and marketing strategies
- Identified clients needs based upon cost and project baselines
- Assisted in development of web interfaces, graphics, and application designs

May 2001 – Aug 2002 Technical Manager / Web Developer Able Management Company Huntsville, Texas

Technical support, web design, and networking for retail / wholesale glass company and online ammunition reseller. Four retail, two wholesale sites and management office.

Highlights of Responsibilities

- Web Site Design & Management
- Managed company network and servers.